



Gianluca Spendolini

Nationality: Italian Date of birth: 11/09/2001 Gender: Male

Phone number: (+39) 3315872489

Email address: gianluca.spendolini.01@gmail.com

• Home: 20093 Cologno Monzese (Italy)

ABOUT ME

I am a curious person and open to continuous learning through study and new experiences. I undertook the course of study focused on biomedical informatics because these topics of direction particularly fascinated me, and were the stimulus to lead me to change the orientation previously chosen. In particular, the fields of interest to me are: software development and creation, machine learning and AI, augmented and virtual reality, big data, etc.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Diploma in Biomedical Informatics 4.0

Foundation of the Higher Technical Institute for New Life Technologies [02/11/2022 – 30/07/2024]

Address: Via Europa, 15, 24125, Bergamo, Bergamo (Italy) | Website: https://www.fondazionebiotecnologie.it/ |

Final grade: 100/100 | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

Diploma in Chemistry, Materials and Biotechnology art. Health Biotechnology

ITSOS Marie Curie [09/2015 – 17/06/2021]

Address: Via Masaccio, 4, 20063 Cernusco sul Naviglio (Italy) | Website: https://www.itsos-mariecurie.edu.it/

Final grade: 68/100

WORK EXPERIENCE

Clinical Research Informatics Unit

Mario Negri Institute [05/02/2024 - Current]

City: Ranica | Country: Italy | Website: https://www.marionegri.it/

During the internship I was responsible for hardware and software assistance to the staff, network administration, installation/configuration and updating of programs and help desk activities. I also participated in the development and maintenance of the source code of web programs dedicated to clinical studies or the center's activity, working mainly on the security of saved data (encryption and decryption thanks to AES-based functions) and the addition of new features (such as communication between the internal system and external systems using REST API technology).

After the end of the internship period in collaboration with ITS Nuove Tecnologie della Vita, I was offered a scholarship. In addition to the activities described above, I participated in the validation of the web system that I deal with.

Laboratory technician

Sun Chemical [01/12/2021 – 28/02/2022]

City: Caleppio di Settala | Country: Italy | Website: https://www.sunchemical.com/

The role I played consisted of preparing samples of various types of inks as part of an MSA project.

LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

CS50 Certificate for CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript

Release date: December 25, 2024

Link: https://cs50.harvard.edu/certificates/faf4147e-af8a-44ff-b988-2bbded9bd889

CS50 Certificate for CS50's Introduction to Programming with Python

Release date: November 15, 2024

Link: https://cs50.harvard.edu/certificates/609d216c-9b4f-45a1-931b-89c23ade17af

CS50 Certificate for CS50's Introduction to Cybersecurity

Release date: January 22, 2024

Link: https://cs50.harvard.edu/certificates/5fca3b47-6ceb-471c-9f7f-4b3c80984679

[24/10/2023 - Current]

CS50's Introduction to Artificial Intelligence with Python Course

edX Verified Certificate for CS50's Introduction to Computer Science

Release date: August 14, 2023

Link: https://courses.edx.org/certificates/458286fff29d44f396463e5f3f23e036

DIGITAL SKILLS

Computer languages

Python (basic knowledge) / C (basic knowledge) / SQL (basic knowledge) / PHP (basic knowledge) / HTML (basic knowledge) / JavaScript (basic knowledge) / CSS (basic knowledge)

Framework

Django (basic knowledge)

DBMS

MySQL (basic knowledge) / SQLite (basic knowledge)

Configurations and Markup

JSON / XML / YAML / Docker Compose

Analysis and management software

Git, GitHub e GitLab (basic knowledge) / Microsoft Excel (basic knowledge)

EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCES

[06/04/2024]

BLSD - basic cardiopulmonary resuscitation and early defibrillation

[21/03/2023 - 18/09/2023]

Together Project - Business Game

I was involved in the design of a container and a stand using AutoCAD.

[12/03/2023]

Safe Driving Beginner - ACI-SARA Safe Driving Center

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Soft Skill

- I engage collaboratively in group activities, identifying the best possible solutions to achieve the shared goal;
- Good communication and interpersonal skills, also improved thanks to the experience gained at the Mario Negri Institute and the course attended at ITS Nuove Tecnologie Della Vita. Equally important in this area are the days of Bergamo Scienza, a significant moment of interaction with the outside world and a further opportunity to train, in a different context, my communication approach;
- I'm natural predisposed to be precise and attentive to details, moreover I can recognize my areas of improvement, which is a incentive to activate myself to acquire new tools and skills based on my priorities.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Hard Skill

- Good knowledge of data management techniques (MySQL database) acquired during the internship at the Mario Negri Institute;
- Good knowledge of containerization techniques (Docker and Docker Compose);
- · Ability to acquire data and analyze results quantitatively and qualitatively to identify cause-effect relationships;
- Ability to analyze, research and process data from multiple sources, using a diverse range of analysis tools;
- Expertise in project and activity control, with attention to compliance with environmental protection and safety regulations;
- Ability to draft detailed technical reports and accurate documentation of activities performed, both individually and in groups;
- Critical evaluation of the value, limits and risks of technical solutions to improve the quality of social life and ensure safety in living and working places;
- Active participation in the management of laboratory activities, including supervision of chemical and biotechnological processes.

I authorize the processing of my personal data in the CV pursuant to art. 13 Legislative Decree 30 June 2003 n. 196 - "Codice in materia di protezione dei dati personali" and art. 13 GDPR 679/16 - "Regolamento europeo sulla protezione dei dati personali"